sidney alcantara

FRONT-END SOFTWARE ENGINEER

email sidney@sidney.me mobile 0478117993 github @notseenee website sidney.me

about

Front-end software engineer passionate about the intersection of technology and design. Interested in building consumer software and user experiences that make life easier. Self-taught web development and UI/UX design. Coding on the web since 2010.

experience

Antler

Sydney

A global startup generator that connects entrepreneurs to build innovative tech solutions.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

2020 - PRESENT

- Developing new React web portals used by program members globally.
- Developing Firetable, a Firestore GUI for internal use and available open source.

2hats Sydney

A former Sydney startup that connected talented uni students and recent graduates to other startups that need people who can make an immediate impact to their business.

FULL STACK ENGINEER

JUL - NOV 2019

- Led development on a complete redesign of the student-facing web portal to improve user experience and retention. Improved rate of user base growth by 150%.
- Refactored code to TypeScript and improved documentation to optimise development.
- Maintained and extended back-end serverless architecture to meet new business goals.
- Interviewed and assessed candidates. Directly facilitated a core business function.
- Presented company tech talk at a leading university. Featured in company's online ads.

JUNIOR FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

AUG 2018 - JUL 2019

- Co-developed new React web portal a month before launch. Grew user base by 40%.
- Assisted in code refactoring to React Hooks from Redux just as it was first released.
 Reduced amount of code written by 30% and halved JS payload size.
- Developed a minimal, clean design language for the company's web portals.
- Learnt and built on top of a serverless architecture with Google Cloud Firestore, Cloud Functions and CI/CD with Bitbucket Pipelines on the job without prior experience.
- Promoted the company at university events, actively driving sign ups and engagement.

skills

- Front-end web development. React + Hooks, responsive CSS + SCSS, ES6+, TypeScript. npm modules, semantic HTML, browser compatibility, web performance.
- Implementing UI/UX designs. Strong attention to detail and typography. Pixel-perfect recreations of designs. Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, XD, Sketch.
- Team-based development and collaboration. Git. Strong communication skills.
- Back-end web development. Google Cloud Firestore + Functions, Node.js. CI/CD with Bitbucket Pipelines, Netlify. Also familiar with Python, Bash shell.

education Bachelor of Advanced Computing

THE UNIVERSITY OF SYDNEY

2018 - 22

Received Sydney Scholars Award and accepted into Dalyell Scholars program.